<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
 <id>io.github.Qalculate.qalculate-qt</id>
 <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
 <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
 <name>Qalculate! (Qt UI)</name>
 <name xml:lang="ca">Qalculate! (Qt UI)</name>
 <name xml:lang="de">Qalculate! (Qt UI)</name>
 <name xml:lang="es">Qalculate! (Qt UI)</name>
 <name xml:lang="fr">Qalculate! (Qt UI)</name>
 <name xml:lang="pt_BR">Qalculate! (Qt UI)</name>
 <name xml:lang="ru">Qalculate! (Интерфейс Qt)</name>
 <name xml:lang="sl">Qalculate! (vmesnik Qt)</name>
 <name xml:lang="sv">Qalculate! (Qt UI)</name>
 <name xml:lang="zh_CN">Qalculate! (Qt UI)</name>
 <summary>Powerful and easy to use calculator</summary>
 <summary xml:lang="ca">Calculadora poderosa i fàcil a usar</summary>
 <summary xml:lang="de">Leistungsstarker und einfach zu bedienender Taschenrechner</summary>
 <summary xml:lang="es">Calculadora poderosa y fácil de usar</summary>
 <summary xml:lang="fr">Une calculatrice puissante et facile d'utilisation</summary>
 <summary xml:lang="nl">Gemakkelijk te gebruiken rekenmachine met veel mogelijkheden</summary>
 <summary xml:lang="pt_BR">Calculadora potente e fácil de usar</summary>
 <summary xml:lang="ru">Мощный и простой в использовании калькулятор</summary>
 <summary xml:lang="sl">Zmogljivo računalo, preprosto za uporabo</summary>
 <summary xml:lang="sv">Kraftfull och användarvänlig miniräknare</summary>
 <summary xml:lang="zh_CN">强大而易用的计算器</summary>
 <description>
  <p>Qalculate! is a multi-purpose cross-platform desktop calculator. It is simple to use but provides power and versatility normally reserved for complicated math packages, as well as useful tools for everyday needs (such as currency conversion and percent calculation).</p>
  <p xml:lang="ca">El Qalculate! és una calculadora d'escriptori per a diverses plataformes i finalitats. És senzill a usar però proporciona poder i versatilitat que normalment es reserva als paquets de matemàtica complicats, així com eines útils per a necessitats diàries (com la conversió de monedes i calculació de percentatge).</p>
  <p xml:lang="de">Qalculate! ist ein vielseitig einsetzbarer, plattformübergreifender Desktop-Rechner. Er ist einfach zu bedienen, bietet aber Leistung und Vielseitigkeit die normalerweise nur für komplizierte mathematische Pakete vorbehalten sind, sowie nützliche ls auch für den täglichen Bedarf (wie Währungsumrechnung und Prozentrechnung).</p>
  <p xml:lang="es">Qalculate! es una calculadora para escritorio multiplataforma y multiuso. Es simple de usar pero dispone de poder y versatilidad normalmente reservada para paquetes de matemática complicados, así como herramientas útiles para necesidades diarias (como conversión de monedas y cálculo de porcentajes).</p>
  <p xml:lang="fr">Qalculate! est une calculatrice de bureau polyvalente et multi-plateforme. Elle est simple d'utilisation mais offre une puissance et une polyvalence normalement réservées aux logiciels de mathématique complexe, ainsi que d'outils utiles au quotidien (tels que la conversion de devises et le calcul de pourcentages).</p>
  <p xml:lang="pt_BR">Qalculate! é uma calculadora para desktop multiplataforma e multiuso. É simples de usar, mas fornece poder e versatilidade normalmente vistas em pacotes de matemática complicados, além de ferramentas úteis para as necessidades diárias (como conversão de moeda e cálculo de porcentagem).</p>
  <p xml:lang="ru">Qalculate! - это универсальный кроссплатформенный настольный калькулятор. Он прост в использовании, но обеспечивает мощность и универсальность, обычно присущие сложным математическим программам, а также полезные инструменты для повседневных нужд (таких как конвертация валют и расчёт процентов).</p>
  <p xml:lang="sl">Qalculate! je večnamensko namizno računalo, ki deluje na več platformah. Je preprosto za uporabo, prinaša pa tako napredna orodja, ponavadi značilna le za kompleksno matematično programje, kot tudi uporabna orodja za vsakodnevne potrebe (npr. pretvorbe valut ali izračun odstotkov).</p>
  <p xml:lang="zh_CN">Qalculate!是一款多功能的跨平台桌面计算器。它简单易用，但却具有通常复杂的数学软件包所需的强大功能和多样性，以及满足日常所需的实用工具(如货币换算和百分比计算)。</p>
  <p>Features include a large library of customizable functions, unit calculations and conversion, physical constants, symbolic calculations (including integrals and equations), arbitrary precision, uncertainty propagation, interval arithmetic, plotting, and a user-friendly interface.</p>
  <p xml:lang="ca">Les característiques inclouen una biblioteca amplia de funcions personalitzables, calculació i conversió d'unitat, constants físics, càlculs simbòlics (incloent integrals i equacions), precisió arbitrària, propagació d'incertesa, aritmètica d'interval, dibuix i una interfície fàcil d'emprar.</p>
  <p xml:lang="de">Zu den Leistungsmerkmalen gehören eine große Bibliothek anpassbarer Funktionen, Einheiten-berechnungen und -umrechnungen, physikalische Konstanten, symbolische Berechnungen (einschließlich Integrale und Gleichungen), beliebige Genauigkeit, Unsicherheits-fortpflanzung, Intervallarithmetik, Plotten und eine benutzerfreundliche Oberfläche.</p>
  <p xml:lang="es">Las características incluyen una gran librería de funciones personalizables, cálculo y conversión de unidades, constantes físicas, cálculos simbólicos (incluyendo integrales y ecuaciones), precisión arbitraria, propagación de incertidumbre, aritmética de intervalos, graficado, y una interfaz amigable.</p>
  <p xml:lang="fr">Les fonctionnalités incluent une grande bibliothèque de fonctions personnalisables, d'unités de calculs et de conversion, de constantes physiques, de calculs symboliques (y compris les intégrales et équations), de précision arbitraire, de propagation des incertitudes, d'arithmétique d'intervalle, de traçage et une interface facile d'utilisation.</p>
  <p xml:lang="pt_BR">Os recursos incluem uma grande biblioteca de funções personalizáveis, cálculos e conversão de unidades, constantes físicas, cálculos simbólicos (incluindo integrais e equações), precisão arbitrária, propagação de erros, aritmética de intervalos, plotagem e uma interface amigável.</p>
  <p xml:lang="ru">Возможности включают большую библиотеку настраиваемых функций, расчёт и преобразование единиц измерения, физические константы, символьные вычисления, включая интегралы и уравнения, произвольную точность, распространение неопределенности, интервальную арифметику, построение графиков и удобный интерфейс.</p>
  <p xml:lang="sl">Program vsebuje obsežno knjižnjico prilagodljivih funkcij, enot, izračunov in pretvorb, fizikalnih konstant, simbolnih izračunov (tudi integrale in enačbe), poljubno natančnost, statistično negotovost, intervalno aritmetiko, grafe in uporabniku prijazen vmesnik.</p>
  <p xml:lang="zh_CN">功能包括大量可定制函数库、单位计算与换算、物理常数、符号计算(包括积分和方程)、高精度计算、误差传递、区间运算、绘图和用户友好的界面。</p>
 </description>
 <screenshots>
  <screenshot type="default">
   <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Qalculate/qalculate.github.io/master/images/qalculate-qt.png</image>
   <caption>The main window with keypad visible</caption>
  </screenshot>
 </screenshots>
 <url type="homepage">https://qalculate.github.io</url>
 <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/Qalculate/qalculate-qt/issues</url>
 <url type="help">https://qalculate.github.io/manual/index.html</url>
 <url type="donation">https://www.paypal.me/HannaKnutsson</url>
 <url type="translate">https://github.com/Qalculate/libqalculate/blob/master/README.translate</url>
 <developer_name>Hanna Knutsson</developer_name>
 <content_rating type="oars-1.0"/>
 <kudos>
  <kudo>HiDpiIcon</kudo>
  <kudo>ModernToolkit</kudo>
  <kudo>UserDocs</kudo>
 </kudos>
 <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.Qalculate.qalculate-qt.desktop</launchable>
 <provides>
  <binary>qalculate-qt</binary>
 </provides>
 <translation type="qt">qalculate-qt</translation>
 <releases>
  <release version="4.5.0" date="2022-12-19">
   <description>
    <p>Changes:</p>
     <ul>
      <li>Use history font for RPN stack list</li>
      <li>Use log() instead of log2() as alternative action on "ln" keypad button</li>
      <li>Conversion to any type of expression (e.g. "1000 BTC to million USD")</li>
      <li>Use current status of limit implicit multiplication setting during parsing of conversion expression</li>
      <li>New SI prefixes (R, r, Q, q)</li>
      <li>New units: ounce force (ozf), rack unit (U)</li>
      <li>Use standard form (sorting) for polynomials</li>
      <li>Improve consistency of behaviour when global units are replaced</li>
      <li>More consistent addition of units to expression without units for unit conversion</li>
      <li>Improvements and fixes for arg() and atan2() functions</li>
      <li>Fix completion (including segfaults) and expression tooltip on Wayland</li>
      <li>Fix RPN mode deactivated after application loses focus</li>
      <li>Fix interpretation of Myr (megayear) and Gyr (gigayear)</li>
      <li>Fix milli- and centimeter of water units</li>
      <li>Fix genvector() with for negative step size or expression as step size/number of steps</li>
      <li>Fix randuniform() function</li>
      <li>Fix automatic/dual fraction format after conversion (e.g. "8 to score")</li>
      <li>Fix inconsistently displayed parsing of "7d 5h" and similar</li>
      <li>Minor bug fixes and feature enhancements</li>
     </ul>
   </description>
  </release>
  <release version="4.4.0" date="2022-10-17">
   <description>
    <p>Changes:</p>
     <ul>
      <li>Add "Clear history" to available keyboard shortcut and button actions</li>
      <li>Add option, in keypad button menu, to reset keypad position</li>
      <li>Show exchange rates source, and update time, for current calculation in tooltip</li>
      <li>New prime number functions: primePi(), primes(), nthprime(), nextprime(), prevprime(), and isprime()</li>
      <li>New functions for intervals and uncertainties: upperEndpoint(), lowerEndpoint(), midpoint(), and errorPart()</li>
      <li>Add meter of water and related pressure units, and more derived flow rate units</li>
      <li>Support for vectors and matrices in uncertainty propagation calculation</li>
      <li>Proper support for uncertainty propagation in total(), sum(), product(), and for() functions</li>
      <li>Simplify display of parsed expression (primarily for quantities with units)</li>
      <li>Avoid parsing of implicit multiplication as nested multiplication</li>
      <li>Allow use of curly brackets as alternative parentheses</li>
      <li>Include +/- statement in function argument without parentheses</li>
      <li>Return values for approximate variables in exact mode in dimension() and elements()</li>
      <li>Improve parsing of quotation marks as feet/inch or arcmin/arcsec (e.g. do not parse s" as sin)</li>
      <li>Partial Georgian translation</li>
      <li>Fix removal of additional keyboard shortcuts, after first removal</li>
      <li>Fix font dialogs when "Keep above other windows" is enabled</li>
      <li>Fix saving of sub-function precalculate property</li>
      <li>Fix exact calculation of re((a*i)^(n/2)) (wrong sign in some cases)</li>
      <li>Fix erroneous calculation in some cases with physical constants both outside and inside unit relations when interval calculation is set to interval arithmetic</li>
      <li>Fix segfault in Calculator destructor</li>
      <li>Fix segfaults in some corner cases</li>
      <li>Fix use of random numbers in iterative functions</li>
      <li>Fix writing beyond end of array during exchange rates check in some cases (results in activation of old style matrices)</li>
      <li>Fix automatic reactivation of deactivated global object if a function with the same name exists</li>
      <li>Do not convert function arguments which do not allow units (fixes "arcsin(0.5+/-0.1) to deg")</li>
      <li>Fix prefix after conversion to optimal unit when the optimal unit includes a prefix</li>
      <li>Fix exact calculation when function argument is an approximate vector variable (fail)</li>
      <li>Minor bug fixes and feature enhancements</li>
     </ul>
   </description>
  </release>
  <release version="4.3.0" date="2022-08-22">
   <description>
    <p>Changes:</p>
     <ul>
      <li>Fix handling of Unicode powers for units in denominator, with adaptive parsing enabled (e.g. parse 10m/s² the same as 10m/s^2)</li>
      <li>Fix "+" ignored after "E" in number bases where "E" is a digit</li>
      <li>Fix scientific E notation with sign in argument when function is used without parentheses</li>
      <li>Fix lambertw() for values very close to zero</li>
      <li>Fix a*b^x+cx=d when a and c have different signs and d is non-zero</li>
      <li>Fix a^x+b^x=c when a and b is negative, and c is positive</li>
      <li>Fix segfaults in some corner cases</li>
      <li>Fix potential issues in handling of leap seconds (e.g. during subtraction of seconds from date)</li>
      <li>Fix name field not working in argument edit dialog</li>
      <li>var=a syntax for variable assignment with calculated expression</li>
      <li>Replace ounce with fluid ounce during conversion to volume unit</li>
      <li>Solve a^x+b^x+...=c in more cases</li>
      <li>Improve remainder/modulus for numerators with large exponents</li>
      <li>Truncate number in output of parsed expression and end with ellipsis if unable to display all decimals</li>
      <li>Improved floating point calculation and output speed, particularly for simple expressions with very high precision</li>
      <li>New functions: clip(), qFormat(), qError()</li>
      <li>Replace selection (instead of wrap in parentheses) on operator input if selection ends with operator</li>
      <li>Act as if two arguments are required when applying base-N logarithm to expression</li>
      <li>Show padlock (or "[P]") after protected expression</li>
      <li>Minor bug fixes and feature enhancements</li>
     </ul>
   </description>
  </release>
  <release version="4.2.0" date="2022-05-25">
   <description>
    <p>Changes:</p>
     <ul>
      <li>Variable spacing of x values in plot (unless step size is used)</li>
      <li>Option to plot real and imaginary parts separately (enabled by default)</li>
      <li>Updated plot() function with arguments for specification of plot options (in any order after the third argument)</li>
      <li>Polar plot style</li>
      <li>Ask the user for the desired sinc() variant (unnormalized or normalized)</li>
      <li>Support for binary-coded decimals (BCD)</li>
      <li>Show names with underscore capitalized and with underscore removed (with some exceptions)</li>
      <li>Additional information units</li>
      <li>Units for volumetric flow rate</li>
      <li>Tradtional numbers (e.g. dozen, score)</li>
      <li>Show warning when log() is used with a single argument, and always show second argument of log()</li>
      <li>Make names with a single character followed by digits case-sensitive with suffix by default</li>
      <li>Accept more than two arguments in gcd() and lcm()</li>
      <li>Interpret a single vector argument as a list of arguments if function requires more than one argument</li>
      <li>Insert minus instead of executing RPN operation, on key press, when last character is e</li>
      <li>Updated Tab key behaviour, e.g. cycle through completion items on subsequent tab key presses, and traverse items if tab key is unbound</li>
      <li>Fix segfault when result is a currency with quantity of one</li>
      <li>Fix copy keyboard shortcut in expression entry</li>
      <li>Fix limit of floor(), ceil(), and trunc()</li>
      <li>Fix plotting of derivatives and integrals</li>
      <li>Fix randpoisson()</li>
      <li>Fix reactivation of object, after object that caused deactivation is removed</li>
      <li>Minor bug fixes and feature enhancements</li>
     </ul>
   </description>
  </release>
  <release version="4.1.1" date="2022-04-04">
   <description>
    <p>Changes:</p>
     <ul>
      <li>Improve resolution and sizing of flag images</li>
      <li>Do nothing when Enter is pressed if expression is empty</li>
      <li>Restrict use of reciprocal in unit conversion, e.g. invert in "5m/s to s/m" (= 0.2 s/m) but not in "500/lb to g" (= 1.1/g)</li>
      <li>New mHg unit (allows use with prefixes other than milli)</li>
      <li>Always display abbreviated unit name (symbol) with abbreviated prefix (when unit only has short name)</li>
      <li>Minor improvements to automatic unit conversion</li>
      <li>Fix display of (1 + f(x))/n</li>
     </ul>
   </description>
  </release>
  <release version="4.1.0" date="2022-03-14">
   <description>
    <p>Changes:</p>
     <ul>
      <li>Add option to show both parsed and entered (or only one) expression in history</li>
      <li>Add option to clear expression history</li>
      <li>Do not add duplicate results to history</li>
      <li>Improved result copying, with proper html format and ASCII option</li>
      <li>Do not replace *, -, / with Unicode operators if cursor is within quotation marks (apply same principles on paste)</li>
      <li>Do not perform automatic (continuous) conversion, from conversion view, if result contains no unit</li>
      <li>Use non-breaking narrow space as digit separator in reasonably short numbers, and between quantity and unit</li>
      <li>Improve appearance of icons with display scaling</li>
      <li>Update value of austronomical unit</li>
      <li>Fix segfault with local digit grouping when separator is empty (e.g. with ignore locale)</li>
      <li>Fix freezes and crashes with extrememly large vectors and matrices</li>
      <li>Fix segfault in matrix multiplication</li>
      <li>Minor bug fixes and feature improvements</li>
     </ul>
   </description>
  </release>
  <release version="4.0.0" date="2022-02-14">
   <description>
    <p>Changes:</p>
     <ul>
      <li>Programming and algebra keypads</li>
      <li>Customizable keypad</li>
      <li>Customizable keyboard shortcuts</li>
      <li>Option to hide number pad (right part of keypad)</li>
      <li>Workspace (mode, history, and temporary variables) can now be saved (to a single file)</li>
      <li>New matrix syntax (column separated by space or comma, rows separated by semicolon, as in matlab)</li>
      <li>Do not make any difference between a vector and a matrix with a single row, or between a scalar and matrix with a single element</li>
      <li>Support input of functions, units, and variables with underscores omitted in names (e.g. µ0 = µ_0, FermiCoupling = fermi_coupling), with some exceptions</li>
      <li>Option to disable "simplified" percentage calculations (e.g. interpret 100 + 20% as 100 + 0.2 instead of 100 × 120%)</li>
      <li>Option to truncate numbers (instead of round to nearest) in result</li>
      <li>Convert K, Hz, and 1/m to J (and derived units) using conversion factor constants (e.g. 1/(550nm) to eV ≈ 2.25 eV)</li>
      <li>Allow use of M as 10^6 without unit</li>
      <li>New ksi unit</li>
      <li>New functions: divisors(), rate(), vertcat(), horzcat()</li>
      <li>New plastic number (ρ) constant, and new "hbar" name for reduced Planck constant, and add second Unicode codepoint for µ-sign in constants</li>
      <li>Allow zero (1st and/or 2nd argument) in comb() and perm(), and return zero if second argument (k) is greater than the first (n)</li>
      <li>Calculate statistical functions (e.g. mode(), min(), max(), percentile()) separately for each column of matrix</li>
      <li>Return the lowest value if there are multiple values with equal frequency in mode()</li>
      <li>Parse text argument as expression if concatenate function name is found in text string, and fix concatenate returning date</li>
      <li>Fix Unicode handling on platforms where char is not signed</li>
      <li>Fix bitrot()</li>
      <li>Fix segfault in multisolve() when initial order of equations is not optimal</li>
      <li>Fix segfault with empty sqrt inside sqrt, e.g. sqrt(1+sqrt())</li>
      <li>Fix incompletely calculated nounit(), e.g. in unit conversion</li>
      <li>Minor bug fixes and feature improvements</li>
     </ul>
   </description>
  </release>
  <release version="3.22.0" date="2021-12-01">
   <description>
    <p>Changes:</p>
     <ul>
      <li>Unit and data set creation/editing</li>
      <li>Complete variable and functions editing</li>
      <li>Percentage calculation dialog</li>
      <li>Periodic table</li>
      <li>Show result in expression status tooltip (calculate-as-you-type)</li>
      <li>Horizontal toolbar with added units and plot buttons</li>
      <li>Favorite functions, units, and variables (shown in toolbar menus)</li>
      <li>Ctrl+Enter shortcut for approximation of current result</li>
      <li>New functions: linearfit(), quadraticfit(), cubicfit(), ramlatency(), parallel()</li>
      <li>Improved and extended parallel operator (|| is interpreted as parallel if units are used)</li>
      <li>Merged inv() and inverse() functions</li>
      <li>Allow nested subfunctions</li>
      <li>Solve x^(x^(-a))=b</li>
      <li>Fix pearson() and spearman()</li>
      <li>Fix a*sin(x)+b*cos(x)=c</li>
      <li>Fix display of incompletely solved equation with dual approximation in some cases</li>
      <li>Many minor feature enhancements and bug fixes</li>
     </ul>
   </description>
  </release>
  <release version="3.21.0" date="2021-10-13">
   <description>
    <p>Changes:</p>
     <ul>
      <li>Show result index in history (click to insert value)</li>
      <li>Remove paste icons from history</li>
      <li>Double-click to insert history text</li>
      <li>Add insert value and insert text to history context menu</li>
      <li>Option to remove, protect, or move history item to top</li>
      <li>History search</li>
      <li>If there is no selection, copy the result/expression at cursor when using context menu</li>
      <li>Options to use (middle) dot as multiplication sign and regular slash character as division sign</li>
      <li>Move keypad button to last position in toolbar</li>
      <li>Ask (once) for correct interpretation of ambiguous implicit multiplication</li>
      <li>Improved simplification of radical expressions</li>
      <li>Improved Im(), Re(), and arg() functions</li>
      <li>Improved output of complex forms (other than the default rectangular) in exact mode</li>
      <li>Immediately return memory on MR clicked if entire expression was unchanged (or empty)</li>
      <li>Function for drill bit size conversion</li>
      <li>Fix crash when using the dock menu to show the RPN dock stack for the first time</li>
      <li>Fix link in new version dialog</li>
      <li>Fix parenthesis highlighting when cursor is at end of expression</li>
      <li>Fix initial value of interval display in preferences dialog</li>
      <li>Fix saving of approximation mode</li>
      <li>Fixes for equations with complex inverse trigonometric and hyperbolic functions with no solution</li>
      <li>Fixes for complex x^(ax)=b</li>
      <li>Fixes for localization on Windows</li>
      <li>Minor bug fixes and feature improvements</li>
     </ul>
   </description>
  </release>
  <release version="3.20.0" date="2021-07-28">
   <description>
    <p>Initial version of the Qt user interface.</p>
   </description>
  </release>
 </releases>
</component>
